Brandon Lee Piercy

Los Angeles, CA | b.piercy567@gmail.com | <u>brandon.im</u> | <u>github.com/brandonleepiercy</u>/ | <u>linkedin.com/in/brandon-piercy-8713a1130/</u> | (805) 245-9451

EDUCATION

University of California, Los Angeles Extension | Full-Stack Web Development | Result: A- | 09/2020 - 01/2021 **Relevant Coursework:** HTML/CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node, Express, REST API, MySQL, MongoDB, React.js, Handlebars, Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming

University of California, Santa Barbara | B.A. Communication | 09/2016 - 09/2020

Relevant Coursework: Organizational Communication, Interpersonal Communication, Study Design,

Statistical/Regression Analytics, Marketing Strategies, Social Media Communication, Corporate Social

Responsibility, Legal Communication, Communication and Gender, Macroeconomics, Microeconomics, Accounting,

Financial Markets

SUMMARY

Web Developer with skills in front-end and back-end of building web applications that follow best practices. Over 200 hours completed with UCLA's Full-Stack Web Development program. Proficient in Javascript, HTML, CSS and other popular libraries like React.js, Node.js, Bootstrap and jQuery. Strong understanding of SQL, Mongo and proper construction of web servers. Also a recent college graduate with a degree in Communication and education in Economics and Accounting. Has experience working in teams, and as a leader in a variety of environments. I am a passionate individual with excellent communication and teamwork skills and an ability to learn anything. I am very responsive to constructive criticism, and I have no problem with decision making or being in a support role.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS3, SQL

Frameworks/Systems: React, Bootstrap, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS, Heroku, REST

API, Git Flow, App Wireframing

Principles: Object Oriented Programming, SEO and traffic analytics, Web Servers, Algorithms and Data Structures

Foreign Languages: Mandarin (Speaking: +++, Reading/Writing: +)

PROJECTS

Snippet | https://snippet.ltd | https://github.com/ma-wong/project-3

- Snippet is an app that allows users to sign up for an account and post snippets of code to a SQL database, where other users can view and comment
- Led a team of 4 through the wireframing design process with Figma
- Ensured the app followed the MVC paradigm and general good practices for clean code
- Built the API end-points and routes for the Sequelize models
- Handled the Node package scripts to debug Heroku deployment
- Built the front end and back end for the NavBar and the Create Code page

IceBox https://infinite-castle-57105.herokuapp.com https://github.com/brandonleepiercy/sneaker-wikipedia

- IceBox is an encyclopedia for limited release sneakers, users can search for a specific sneaker with various different parameters
- Came up with the concept for the application and led developer meetings throughout the project
- Managed the timing of commits and pushes from other developers to avoid Git conflicts
- Resolved all the Git conflicts that did arise
- Debugged the full-stack
- Created the logic to dynamically render the selected shoe page
- Created the API endpoints for the SQL models
- Created design elements to complete the front-end of the site

Work Experience

Cali Culture Inc | Santa Barbara, CA | 01/2018 - 06/2018

- Started CaliCulture, a fully licensed and accredited medical marijuana delivery service with the help of two other UCSB students. CaliCulture had 6 employees at the peak.
- Handled all matters dealing with the POS, tracking inventory, accounting sales, handling cash, paying taxes, taking phone orders, dispatching drivers, managing customer service, marketing online, managing the online storefront, securing inventory, and managing employees.

Jersey Mike's Subs | Santa Barbara, CA | 09/2018 - 03/2019

Crew Member: Cooked/Assembled all subs, handled payment, and clean-up responsibilities.

Swim Coach | San Jose, CA | 05/2014 - 08/2017

- Swim Instructor: Taught individuals ages 4 60 basic water safety, and four strokes.
- Competitive Coach: Managed/coached a competitive team of 60 70 1st grade 12th grade swimmers

DoorDash Driver | San Jose, CA & Santa Barbara, CA | 05/2016 - 09/2019